Shoot
Down
Shoot Down!
Shoot
Down
Kita High got knocked out
in the first round?
（男性Ａ）北(きた)高が１回戦敗退か…
Getting beat 0-3...
（男性Ｂ）
０−３のストレート負け　残念だな
That's gotta hurt.
（典馬(てんま)の泣き声）
（典馬）すんませんでした
I'm sorry...
Tenma, snap out of it.
（米村(よねむら)）典馬　切り替えろ
You're still in the individual tournament.
（米村）お前には個人戦も
残ってるし 来年だってあるんだ
And you can compete next year, too.
（典馬）来年じゃ
先輩たち いないじゃないスか！
But next year...
You guys won't be here!
None of you are pathetic!
“情けなくなんかねえ”
You guys, the school, my brother...
“先輩も北高も兄貴も
俺の全部が誇らしい”って—
You are all my pride and joy!
And I wanted to show the world that!
見せつけてやりたかった！
ちくしょう！
Dammit...
（相沢(あいざわ)）ハハハッ…
I had no idea you felt that way.
お前に そんなふうに
思われてるなんて知らなかったよ
We all did the best we could.
やれることは
全部やったつもりなんだけどな
But it wasn't enough.
それでも届かなかった
残ったのは悔しさだけだ
All that's left is disappointment.
これも いつかは
美しい思い出に変わんのかね？
People might say we'll one day
look back on this as a beautiful memory.
But I don't believe a word of it.
絶対ウソだろう！　くそ！
Dammit!
Losing so badly can be tough to take.
（駿海(しゅんかい)）
結果と向き合うのは苦痛が伴う
だが 痛みは本気でやった証拠だ
But that pain shows how
earnest your efforts were.
Victory is preferable, but there
is value in facing up to a loss.
（駿海）勝利が いちばんだが
向き合った敗北にも価値は生まれる
この敗北を糧にしろよ
Use this defeat to grow as warriors.
Team Tournament
Round 2
（アナウンス）
以上 ３対０で 東 大太刀(おおだち)の勝ち
Match over. Odachi,
on the east side, wins 3-0.
（天王寺(てんのうじ)）
ええチームやで ほんまに
They're one amazing team.
They're not the complete package,
but they've got momentum.
（天王寺）
未完成ゆえの勢い　無視できへんな
We'd better not underestimate them.
（加納(かのう)）ああ すごいよ
Yeah, they're really something.
Honestly, though, I'm tired
of seeing people like them.
でも 正直 見飽きたよな
この手の連中は
They gather momentum, win a few,
then act like they're gonna go all the way.
勢いのまま勝ち進み
番狂わせを演じては—
稀(まれ)に 国宝として名乗りを上げる
They sometimes even become
national treasures.
俺たちは
そういう連中を打ち砕き—
But eating guys like them for breakfast
is how we've won six on the trot.
結果を出してきた６連覇の絶対王者
…だろう？
Right?
せやな
Right.
Inter High
Day 2
Team Tournament
Round 3
Team tournament: Round 3.
（アナウンス）
団体戦 三回戦—
On the east side, Kabutoyama High School.
Bout 17
"The One Loved by the Sumo Gods"
東 兜山(かぶとやま)高校
西 大太刀高校
On the west side, Odachi High School.
（小関(おぜき)）オリャー！
Yes!
よし！
（佑真(ゆうま)）ドラァ！
Yes!
（佑真）よし！
（火ノ丸(ひのまる)）ウオッ！
They went three-for-three
in the third round, too!
（男性Ａ）３回戦も３連勝！
With their momentum from yesterday plus
Hinomaru back in action, they're unstoppable!
昨日の勢いに
火ノ丸まで加わって やべえよ！
That injured left arm of his doesn't
seem to be holding him back at all.
（男性Ｂ）
左腕の負傷も問題なさそうだ
Odachi's going all the way!
これは まだまだ行くぞ 大太刀
Fourth bout. On the east side, Yamada-kun.
（アナウンス）副将戦 東…
（礼奈(れいな)）あれ？
Huh?
Didn't we already win?
Why are there more bouts?
On the west side, Kunisaki-kun.
（礼奈）チームとしての
勝ちは決まったのに まだやるの？
From today, they have to fight
all five bouts in each round.
（千鶴子(ちづこ)）今日からの本戦は
５戦全て行われます
He got behind him!
（男性Ａ）後ろ取った！
Four in a row!
（男性Ｂ）４勝目！
（拍手）
（蛍(けい)）ンッ…
（千比路(ちひろ)）よし いってこい
全国デビュー戦だ
Okay, get out there and enjoy your debut
in the national spotlight!
Fifth bout. On the east side, Sato-kun.
（アナウンス）
大将戦 東 佐藤(さとう)君　西 三ツ橋(みつはし)君
On the west side, Mitsuhashi-kun.
Isn't he a little scrawny?
（男性Ａ）細すぎねえか？
I saw this guy in the prefecture prelims.
（男性Ｂ）県予選の動画で見たよ
あいつ 八艘飛(はっそうと)び やるぜ
He leaps up after the initial charge.
This guy's crafty! Be careful!
（選手）
変化あるぞ！　気をつけろ！
（審判）はっきよい！
（蛍）ンンッ！
Spirit!
No tricks this time.
（選手）変化はなし
バレてちゃ跳ぶ意味もねえか
Leaping's useless if you know what's coming.
（蛍）ウワッ！
He sucks!
（男性Ａ）よわっ！
（礼奈）三ツ橋…
Mitsuhashi...
（桐仁(きりひと)）三ツ橋
（蛍）大丈夫ですよ
I'm fine.
I've decided to win with a change-up.
変化で勝つ　僕が決めたことです
（榎木(えのき)のあくび）
Why are you yawning?
Didn't you get any sleep?
おい なんだよ　寝てねえの？
I couldn't stop watching film
of the Nagoya Tournament.
（榎木）いやぁ
名古屋(なごや)場所の録画見てたら
止まんなくて
Daikeisho almost won.
大景勝(だいけいしょう) 惜しかったですよね
（バトムンフ）フン…　どこが？
今の日本人 弱い
How?
Japanese sumo wrestlers weak now.
（バトムンフ）刃皇(じんおう) モンゴル強い
（榎木）はいはい そうですね
Jino, Mongolian wrestler, strong.
Yeah, yeah, you made your point.
だから こうして
頑張ってんじゃないスか 僕らも
That's why we're here, right? To get stronger.
草薙(くさなぎ)
Kusanagi...
Dojikiri.
（狩谷(かりや)）童子切(どうじきり)
（天王寺）“童子切”か
Dojikiri, huh? I don't really like that name.
その呼ばれ方
あんま好きちゃうねん
だって ほら
草薙のが格上っぽいやんか
After all, Kusanagi sounds way cooler.
まあ それも期待の差やろうな
最後の日本人横綱 大和国(やまとくに)の息子
Guess it just shows how much
more they expect of you...
Son of Yamatokuni,
the last Japanese yokozuna.
でも “親父(おやじ)”も“二つ名”も
土俵の上には持ち込めへん
You can't bring your father or
your moniker into the sumo ring.
You're in there all by yourself.
あるのは己のみやで
Tennoji-san, I will...
（久世(くぜ)）天王寺さん　僕は—
横綱の息子であるということを
背負って 土俵に上がります
enter the ring with the weight of being
the son of a yokozuna on my shoulders.
フフフッ…　ほんま 今年の
インターハイはスリリングやで
This year's Inter High is a thrill a minute.
On the east side, Tottori Hakuro High School.
（アナウンス）東 鳥取白楼(とっとりはくろう)高校
Here comes Hakuro.
（男性Ａ）来たぞ　白楼だ
（男性Ｂ）絶対王者のお出ましだ
The invincible champions are up.
（アナウンス）先鋒戦(せんぽうせん) 東 榎木君
First bout. On the east side, Enoki-kun.
（審判）はっきよい！
Spirit!
（礼奈）なに？　今の技は
（千鶴子）あれは合気道です
What kind of move was that?
That was an aikido move.
Sumo's all about knocking
your opponent off-balance.
相撲は重心を崩し合う競技
He's only 174 cm tall,
and he doesn't have a large frame.
身長174センチで
横幅もない彼は—
So he uses aikido, which targets an opponent's
center of gravity regardless of size.
体格によらず
重心を制する合気道を取り入れた
Hakuro's wrestlers use
any technique they see fit.
選手自身が工夫し よいと思えば
何でも取り入れるそうです
I ended up choosing Hakuro because
the team's full of colorful characters.
僕が白楼を選んだ理由は
チームのカラフルさですかね
（礼奈）カラフルさ？
Colorful?
They have technicians like Enoki-san...
榎木さんのような選手が
いるかと思えば…
Second bout.
（アナウンス）二陣戦 東 首藤(しゅとう)君
On the east side, Shuto-kun.
...and fighters who are
all about brute strength.
（千鶴子）こんな単純明快な選手も
なるほど　カラフルね
I get it now. Colorful characters, indeed.
ウチは毎年 全国から
いろんなヤツらが集まってきます
Every year, lots of interesting
sumo wrestlers come to our school.
International students from Mongolia
海を渡って モンゴルからも
give the team even more variety.
それが またチームに多彩さを生み
切磋琢磨(せっさたくま)に拍車がかかる
It motivates us to compete.
I'm glad I'm part of Hakuro.
白楼に来て良かった
心から そう思います
I say that from the bottom of my heart.
（佑真）練習場 空いてるよな？
確認しようぜ
They've opened up the practice area.
Let's go check it out.
（千比路）その前にメシだ メシ！
Before that, let's get some grub!
Wow, even Hakuro's might
doesn't scare you, does it?
（沙田(さだ)）さすが
白楼の強さにも のまれてないね
（火ノ丸）あっ…　沙田
Sada.
You're heading over
to the practice area?
（沙田）練習場 行くんでしょう？
僕らも ついてっていいかな？
Mind if we join you?
ハハハッ…
そんな怪訝(けげん)な顔しないでよ
Don't look so wary.
We actually took a trip out
to Tottori after the prelims.
実は僕ら 予選のあと
遠征で鳥取 行ってきてさ
Tottori? You mean...
（小関）鳥取？　まさか…
How's about, for dessert, we recount
our experiences taking on Hakuro?
白楼と戦った僕らの経験—
食後のデザートとしちゃ
悪くないと思うけどな
The 32 qualifying
competitors will now contest
（アナウンス）
これより 個人戦 32選手による—
決勝トーナメントを開始いたします
the final rounds of the
individual tournament.
Sumo
School
Practice Area
Okay, I think it's about time we got started.
（沙田）
さて それじゃ 始めましょっかね
"The Ishi High – Dachi High Joint
Sparring Session to Take Down Hakuro."
石(いし)高とダチ高の打倒白楼 合同稽古
イエ〜イ！
Yay!
I never agreed to this!
（荒木(あらき)）俺は納得してません！
They're our enemies!
なんだって 敵である こいつらに
わざわざ協力しなきゃいけねえんだ
Why are we helping them out?
（金盛(かなもり)）う〜ん…
He's got a point. We're a rival team.
（小関）確かに俺らは敵同士
なのに どうして？
Why are you helping us?
Because this will benefit
Ishi High, of course.
そりゃ もちろん
石高にもメリットがあるからですよ
メリット？
Benefit?
New Captain Mamiya will explain the details!
（沙田）詳しいことは
間宮(まみや)新主将が話してくれます
You're such a punk for making me
do the annoying bit...
（間宮）てめえ
面倒なことは投げやがって…
It's true that this might help
Dachi High get stronger.
まあ 確かに
ダチ高を強くしちまうかもしれない
でも それ以上に ダチ高に—
But if you push them,
you'll make Hakuro dig deep,
白楼の全力を引き出してもらって
得る情報のほうが—
so we'll see more of what they've got,
which will help us when we face them.
有益だと踏んだんスよ
So that's your plan.
なるほどね
You benefited from training
with Kunisaki, didn't you, Sada?
（間宮）沙田が國崎(くにさき)に協力したのも
メリットあってのことだろう？
Yeah, I can't deny it.
まあ そうッスね
I stole everything I could from
Kunisaki-san when we sparred.
俺だって 國崎さんから
盗めるだけ盗みまくってますから
フン…
（佑真）
そういうことなら礼は言わねえぜ
If that's what you're after,
don't expect us to thank you.
We don't have any reason to refuse.
（小関）
こっちとしては断る理由もないしね
I still don't like the idea of giving Dachi
High more opportunities to celebrate!
（荒木）でも ダチ高が これ以上
いい思いすんのは やっぱムカつく
You got that right.
（真田(さなだ)）ホントにな
Your team was pathetic not so long ago.
お前ら ちょっと前まで
マジで くそ弱かったのによ
Ozeki was your only member,
and he always lost in the first round.
部員は小関１人で 毎回 １回戦負け
And now, you guys are basking
in the national spotlight.
そんなヤツらが 今は“全国”だぜ
すげえよ お前ら
That's incredible.
（真田）
敵としての憎さと同じくらい
力士として 尊敬もしてんだ
The hatred we feel for you as our rivals is
matched by the respect we have for your sumo.
We aren't helping you solely
for our own benefit.
メリットだけで
協力したいわけじゃない
We're cheering you on, Dachi High.
応援させてくれ ダチ高
You want me to be a stand-in for Tennoji?
（金盛）仮想天王寺？　俺がか？
Your physique is closest to his.
体格が いちばん近いですからね
潮(うしお)君もイメージしやすいでしょう
It should help Ushio-kun visualize him.
Okay, I hear you.
（金盛）分かったよ
（真田）
あっ 荒木はいいよ ムリしなくて
No one's forcing you to do this, Araki.
Yeah, don't help them if you don't want to.
（沙田）そだねえ
手伝いたい人だけ手伝えば
I don't want to be left out.
（荒木）俺だけ仲間外れはイヤです
（沙田）ハハハハッ…
実際 仮想天王寺と
稽古できるメリットは大きい
Having a stand-in for
Tennoji will definitely help.
This will help them develop even more.
これは大きな収穫だ
ただ…
But...
優勝するためには 白楼ばかり
見ているわけにはいかない
We can't start thinking only Hakuro
stands between us and the crown.
So he's here, too.
やはり来たか
Eiga University High School's...
栄華(えいが)大附属高校—
Kuze Sosuke.
久世草介(そうすけ)
The son of a yokozuna.
（柴木山(しばきやま)）横綱の息子
He's at the age where
he wants to defy his parents.
あのくらいの年ごろなら
親に反抗したくなるもんさ
（柴木山）それが どうだい
Looks to me like...
he's got the same bearing
as you did at your peak.
現役時代のお前そのものじゃねえか
なあ？　大和国
What do you think, Yamatokuni?
I hear he plans to join the pro league
after he becomes high school yokozuna.
“高校横綱になったら—”
“角界入りする”なんて
抜かしてるらしいな
冗談に聞こえねえのが恐ろしいよ
The fact that it doesn't
come across as a joke is scary.
I'm a sucker for my son.
（大和国）私も親バカですから
I thought there wouldn't be anyone
his age who could challenge him.
同世代で息子と張り合える者など
いないと思っていたんですよ
That is, until I came here.
ここに来るまではね
The individual tournament, semifinal.
（アナウンス）個人戦 準決勝
東 天王寺君
On the east side, Tennoji-kun.
On the west side, Kuze-kun.
西 久世君
なかなか どうして…
I get the feeling...
大相撲の未来は明るい
...the future of professional sumo is bright.
Wh-Why is everyone so excited?
な… なに？　この盛り上がりは
まるで 大相撲の横綱対決です
This is the equivalent of
a fight between yokozuna.
Undefeated in official bouts,
and treading the path of a champion.
（柴木山）いまだ公式戦無敗のまま
王道を駆け上がる大横綱の息子と
The son of a great yokozuna.
百戦錬磨の覇王との頂上決戦
Facing a battle-hardened
king of conquerors.
This duel will decide who's best.
（審判）はっきよい！
（２人）ンンッ！
Spirit!
Truth be told, I'd rather these
two didn't fight each other.
（桐仁）できれば この２人には
当たってほしくはなかった
予感がする
I'm having a premonition.
This battle will produce
an even more fearsome monster.
この戦いの果てに
更なる怪物が生まれる
Wondering what's happening...
（駿海）気になるか？
（火ノ丸）あっ…
（駿海）２人の戦いが
（金盛たち）うん？
...in their bout?
They've left you in their wake.
（駿海）
お前だけ置いていかれちまったな
And that's not all. This battle
may put you even further behind.
それどころか この一戦で
更に その差が開くかもしれん
So, tomorrow, how are
you going to beat the guy
…で 昨日 全力で敗れた相手に
どうやって あした 勝つつもりだ？
you threw everything
at yesterday to no avail?
Just like you taught me,
I've been thinking it over.
師匠の教えどおり 考えていました
Ever since the moment I lost.
負けた瞬間から ずっと
全力でも なお 天王寺の底を
見ることさえ かなわなかった
Even going all-out against him, I wasn't
able to see the limit of Tennoji's strength.
But thanks to everyone here,
I've realized something.
でも ここにいる みんなのおかげで
今日 気づけたことがある
I have an inner strength that
I haven't managed to tap into yet.
“まだ見せていない—”
“ワシ自身
自覚していなかった強さが—”
“ワシの中にある”と
Sada, let's have a bout.
沙田　立ち合ってくれ 全力でな
No holding back.
I'm gonna take another step forward
（火ノ丸）今ここで
ワシも踏み出してみせます
in order to get closer to them!
ヤツらに並び立つ１歩を
Let's see what you've got.
見せてもらうとしよう
You're the one best suited to
finding your own style of sumo.
お前の相撲を見つけられるのは
お前自身をおいて ほかにないんだ
Now, show me...
いま一度 見せてくれ
更なる火ノ丸相撲を
The new and improved Hinomaru sumo!
（天王寺）おら！
A leg technique?
足技！？
I expected Tennoji to be more composed.
天王寺は もっと落ち着いた相撲を
取ると思っていたが…
何だ？　この荒々しさは
Why's he being so erratic?
（沙田）天王寺には２つの顔がある
（火ノ丸）うん？
Tennoji has two faces.
When we sparred in Tottori,
I got to see both of them.
（沙田）鳥取遠征で戦ったとき
俺は体感したんだ
One face is the style he uses
to make sure he doesn't lose.
ひとつは 今の“負けない相撲”
He sees what his opponent does
相手の出方に応じて 確実に
有利な体勢を作ってから 前に出る
and picks a strategy that
will give him an advantage.
相手を研究し
慎重に負ける確率を下げて戦う
He researches his opponent thoroughly,
and fights in a way that
plays the percentage game.
As a result, he's undefeated
in his high school sumo career.
結果 高校無敗
But two years ago,
でも 天王寺は ２年前—
when he went up against upperclassmen
and wrestlers stronger than him,
上級生や格上を相手に
見せていたのは もうひとつの顔
he showed a different face:
A style he uses to win.
“勝つ相撲”だ
I like to counterattack,
and have more of a defensive style.
俺の相撲も
カウンターを狙うタイプで—
どちらかというと守りの相撲だ
だから
天王寺が先に攻めるよう しむけた
That's why I tried to make
Tennoji go on the offensive.
そうして引き出し—
The array of attacks he rained down
on me was absolutely brutal.
体感した あの人の攻めは
あまりに狂暴で…
Even thinking back on it
sends chills down my spine.
今 思い出しても背筋が凍る
So this is the champion,
（狩谷）これが王者…
（久世）クッ！
（狩谷）童子切！
Dojikiri.
（歓声）
鬼丸(おにまる)との一戦でも…
In his bout with Onimaru...
いや　今までの どの試合でも
よぎらなかったのに…
No, he didn't waver in any of his bouts.
Is Sosuke really going to lose?
まさか負けるのか？
草介が
ワシの知るかぎり—
As far as I know,
Tennoji Shido is the strongest sumo
wrestler competing in high school sumo.
高校相撲の土俵において
天王寺獅童(しどう)が最強の力士じゃ
However... no one in that arena...
ただ 会場にいる誰も
戦ったワシさえも—
not even me, someone who's fought him...
knows the true limits
of Kuze Sosuke's strength.
久世草介の全力を知らない
Yamatokuni?
大和国！？
What is this? My blood should be boiling.
（久世）何だろう？
血が高ぶっているはずなのに—
同時に すごく落ち着いている
And yet, I feel so calm.
（柴木山）大和国そのものってのが
いよいよ比喩じゃなくなってきたぜ
That comparison to Yamatokuni
is starting to come true!
He's not like Hinomaru or Tennoji.
火ノ丸や天王寺とも違う
He's frighteningly quiet during the bout,
戦いの中にありながら
恐ろしく静かで—
何事にも動じぬ強さを秘めた目
and his eyes reveal
an unwavering strength.
静謐(せいひつ)の相
A look of total serenity.
Attacking creates openings.
（咲(さき)）
攻めてるときにこそ隙は生まれる
My brother calls that a weakness,
兄貴は
それを“弱さ”と言うけど—
but when he used to abandon defense
and fought only on instinct...
守りを捨て 本能だけで戦う—
He was much scarier back then!
あのころのほうが 私は怖かったよ
（火ノ丸）どっちが勝とうが
ワシのやることは ひとつ！
No matter who wins,
my path is laid out in front of me.
Keep on doing things that
excite me, Ushio Hinomaru!
（沙田）いつまでも 俺を
ワクワクさせてくれよ 潮火ノ丸！
Let's go!
（沙田）いくよ！
（火ノ丸）沙田　ありがとうよ！
Sada!
Thank you!
They've moved apart.
距離ができた　出し惜しみはない
No holding back now.
This will be their second
２度目にして
恐らく最後の正面衝突！
and probably final head-on charge!
Kusanagi came off best!
草薙が勝った！
They were evenly matched
on the first charge!
立ち合いでは互角だったのに！
Tennoji's strength brought out
the beast within Sosuke!
天王寺の強さが
草介の底力を目覚めさせた！
He went low?!
低い！
I awakened the beast?
（天王寺）俺が目覚めさせた？
いや 違う！
Not at all!
The beast has awoken for me!
（天王寺）
俺のために目覚めてくれたんや！
That's the super-low
attack my brother perfected
（咲）兄貴が潮君のように
小さかった時代に磨いた—
when he was short like Ushio-kun.
超低空の攻め
Only he can pull it off,
because he used to be so short.
小兵から成長した兄貴やから
できる相撲
その威力は 絶大！
Its intensity... is boundless!
It's working! He's taking too many hits.
効いてる！
いくら何でも受け過ぎだ！
Every strike from the champion...
王者の攻め　そのひとつひとつが
確実に草介を削って…
is chipping away at Sosuke.
Those years when I was shorter than
everyone else has made me strong.
（天王寺）小さかった あのころが
今の俺を強くした
This battle will have the same effect.
この一戦も そうなんや
最強への試練！
It will make me the strongest!
I must battle a clone of Yamatokuni,
the greatest yokozuna of the Heisei era.
平成(へいせい)の大横綱
大和国の分身との戦い
This is another trial that the
sumo gods have arranged for me!
これも また もっと上に行けと
相撲の神さんが俺に与えた逆境！
He grabbed him!
（咲）捕らえた！
（狩谷）天王寺の形！
Tennoji has the advantage!
（天王寺）
なら 乗り越えたろうやないか！
So I'll overcome it!
I will wear the rope that tells everyone I've
defeated the legendary yokozuna, Yamatokuni!
俺は
伝説･大和国を超えた綱を巻く！
ウッ…　恐ろしい男だ！
What a fearsome competitor...
Even in the face of his opponent's
incredible pressure,
相手のすさまじいプレッシャーに
さらされながらも—
he's still thinking about how
he can win using his ideal sumo.
自分の理想の相撲を
取りきることだけを考えている
It's...
あれは…
My right hand is on his belt.
（久世）右上手(みぎうわて)
父 大和国から受け継いだ最強の型
This is the strongest form I have
inherited from my father, Yamatokuni.
For me, the sumo gods are part
of Yamatokuni's fighting style!
僕にとっての相撲の神は
大和国の相撲の中にある！
（天王寺）守りは捨てとる
上手(うわて)も覚悟のうえや！
I've given up on defense.
I was prepared to let him
get his hand on my belt.
今日 勝って 最強の道を行く！
I'm going to win and continue down
the path to becoming the strongest!
An arm lock throw...
（咲）小手投げと…
（狩谷）上手投げの…
...and an overarm throw!
At the same time!
（咲･狩谷）打ち合い！
（叫び声）
Six Point Torso Slice!
Great Serpent Cleaver!
Did the sumo gods turn
their gaze away from him?
（駿海）こいつは
相撲の神さまに見放されたのか—
相撲をやるには あまりに小さい
He's far too small to do sumo.
His spirit, body, and technique
all have room to grow.
心も体も技も
まだまだ未熟だが—
でも いま一瞬 確かに俺は—
But, in that moment, I saw...
a light surrounding Hinomaru
that will drive away...
火ノ丸に 相撲の神さまを
吹き飛ばす光を見た！
the sumo gods!
Incredible.
すげえ…
That might do it.
（小関）これなら きっと…
（佑真）ああ
Yeah.
（桐仁）成果はあったみてえだな
（火ノ丸）桐仁
Looks like it paid off.
Kirihito.
Coach, what happened
between Tennoji and Kuze?
監督　天王寺と久世の勝負は？
The winner was...
勝ったのは…
A yokozuna is...
（柴木山）横綱とは—
人にして 唯一 しめ縄をその身に
張ることを許された神の依代(よりしろ)
the only person permitted to wear
a sacred rope on their body.
They are divine objects.
Tennoji Shido was indeed loved by the gods.
天王寺獅童は
確かに 神に愛された男だった
Kuze Sosuke AKA Kusanagi was not.
久世草介は… 草薙は そうではない
It is as a god,
神そのものとして
神の化身として…
an embodiment of the divine,
that he reigns over the sumo ring.
土俵に君臨する者！
Well, we figured this was a possibility.
（千比路）まあ
こうなる可能性も考えてはいたがな
We were planning to beat Tennoji,
Kuze and all the rest, anyway!
もとより 天王寺も久世も全員
ぶっ倒して 優勝する予定だろう？
（火ノ丸）グッ…　また負けた
ちくしょう！　もう１回じゃ！
I lost again!
Damn! One more game!
Hinomaru, you suck at this.
（千比路）火ノ丸 弱(よえ)えなぁ
（火ノ丸）
おい 佑真　もっと よく切れ！
Hey, Yuma, cut the cards better!
I hope you're not doing
anything underhanded!
まさかイカサマしとらんだろうな？
Of course not.
（佑真）してねえよ！
（小関）ハハハハッ…
潮が勝つまで終わんないな こりゃ
This card game won't be over till Ushio wins.
ウワッ！
ちょっと のぞかないでくださいよ
H-Hey, no peeking!
Ah, loosen up, dude!
（千比路）気にすんな
The finals are tomorrow, but they
don't seem the least bit nervous.
大事な決戦の前なのに
緊張感ありませんね
Is this really okay?
いいの？　これで
It's fine. If they were nervous now,
they wouldn't last until tomorrow.
（桐仁）いいんスよ
今から緊張してたら
あしたまで もたないでしょう
それに
もう気持ちの心配は要らないよ
And, anyway...
There's no need to worry about
their mental state anymore.
You always got so worked up, saying
you wouldn't lose, wouldn't fold...
昔のお前は負けまいと 折れまいと
いつも１人で とがっていた
But now...
でも 今は…
I'm glad you chose Dachi High, Hinomaru.
ダチ高に入って良かったな　火ノ丸
そろそろ寝とけよ
もう遅いんだから
Time for bed!
It's getting late.
All right!
（火ノ丸）おう
（礼奈）私たちも寝るか
Let's head to bed, too.
（佑真）
あっ ついでに電気消してくれ
Turn off the light while you're up.
Okay.
Thanks.
（火ノ丸）ありがとうな
（一同）うん？
ハハハッ…　何のことだか
What are you on about now?
Seriously.
…だな
Guys, let's win tomorrow!
あしたは勝とうぜ　みんな！
（一同）おう！
Yeah!
This is the first time
we've bathed together.
（小関）
みんなで風呂なんて初めてだな
We're all butt naked!
（火ノ丸）裸のつきあいじゃ！
This isn't so different from usual, though.
（蛍）
いつも 裸みたいなもんですけどね
Coach, aren't you getting in?
監督は入らないんですか？
It's dangerous for me to stay in too long.
（桐仁）湯あたりは危険だからな
（佑真）あっ 國崎！
（千比路）ハハハハッ…
Kunisaki!
You jerk!
（佑真）てめえ！
（桐仁）ウワッ！　ンンッ…
Knock it off, you—
（佑真）いいかげんにしろ！
Next Bout
"How I Win"
（佑真たち）あっ…
（桐仁）ウワーッ！